Atique Ahmed

Lead Full Stack Developer AWS Specialist | 8+ Years Exp.



HARDWORKING

 □ atique1201@gmail.com 8553208493 Kolkata, India Indian

12/01/1990

Married in atique-ahmed-680ba5ab

https://youtube.com/c/codeztech https://github.com/codeztech-atique

https://atiqueahmed.com

SUMMARY

I am a self-starter with strong interpersonal skills. Total 8+ years of exp. I work efficiently both as an individual contributor as well as along with a team. I seek new challenges and try to think out of the box while looking for creative solutions to a given problem. Besides the details given on my youtube channel, I believe in character, values, vision, and action. I am a quick learner and believe in learning from my mistakes for I strongly feel that this virtue will take me ahead in life and my career.

EDUCATION

Apr 2008 - Apr 2011

Bachelor of Computer Application

Pailan College of Management & Technology

Kolkata, India

have completed my Bachelor of Computer Applications(BCA), from Pailan College of Management and Technology with 75% May **2012** - May **2015**

Visvesvaraya Technological University

Masters of Computer Application

Bangalore, India

I have completed my Masters of Computer Applications (MCA), from

The Oxford College of Engineering with 75%

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML CSS Agile & Scrum Data Structure **NodeJS** Angular 14+ MongoDB MeanStack Elasticsearch Kibana **Filebeat** Logstash **Postgrest** Java Spring boot **AWS Cognito** React AWS Dynamodb AWS EC2 AWS Elasticsearch AWS Kibana AWS Lambda **AWS Codecommit AWS Cloudfront AWS** Apigetway AWS S3 **AWS Simple Email Service AWS SNS AWS Cloudformation AWS ROUTE53 AWS Cloudwatch Jenkins** Docker

Websockets Microservices Python

AWS APIGateway

囯

Jul 2015

Jun 2017

 \odot \odot \odot \odot

 \odot \odot \odot \odot

 \odot \odot \odot \odot

_ANGUAGES

English

Amazon Lex

Hindi Bengali

AWARDS Aug **2018 TECHGIG**

Link - https://rb.gy/78db9p

Certificates received from Techgig.

PHP and MYSQL.

IIT BOMBAY Certificates received from IIT BOMBAY for PHP and MYSQL. PHP

and MYSQL Link - https://rb.gy/44wl1i

CCNA

Networkers Homee

CCNA Certificates received. CCNA Course for Networking Link - https://rb.gy/y6zrb1

GUINNESS WORLD RECORD Recognized as a top 10 programmer from Techgig, in June 2017. Also

Link - https://rb.gy/1x0a21 Apr 2015 PUBLISHED JOURNAL IN IJSRD

College Project -Swift Statistic Examiner with Packet Generator & Distribution Graphs Link - https://rb.gy/4tjfu2

received certificate from Guinness World Record.

MOSTLY PROUD OF 8

Github https://github.com/codeztech-atique

63

Leetcode

HackerRank Profile https://www.hackerrank.com/Atique_Ahmed

> **Techgig** https://www.techgig.com/atiqueahmed4

https://leetcode.com/codeztech-atique/

You Tube

StackBlitz

https://stackblitz.com/@codeztech-atique Techmentor on Youtube | Codeztech

https://youtube.com/codeztech

Techmentor on Facebook | Codeztech https://www.facebook.com/CodezTechnology

> Blogger | Codeztech https://www.codeztech.com/

Google Chrome Extension - Easily Access

https://rb.gy/ekku2f

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Codeztech Content

Leadership **Techmentor** Active listening Communication Willingness to learn Teamwork

Motivational speaker

I have done some live project using (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Websocket, Angular 14+ Nodejs and Mongodb, AWS

2. https://asianetnews.com/

https://tamil.asianetnews.com/

Time management

LIVE PROJECTS

Dynamodb, postgrest, Elasticsearch, Kibana, AWS API Gateway, AWS cloudfront, AWS route 53, AWS s3 bucket, AWS EC2). Therefore, I am providing the link below. 1. https://cms.asianetnews.com/

https://telugu.asianetnews.com/ https://kannada.asianetnews.com/ 6. https://hindi.asianetnews.com/

- 7. https://www.mynation.com/ 8. https://newsable.asianetnews.com/
- **DECLARATION**

10. https://rb.gy/8e9xh3

best of my knowledge and belief.

https://bangla.asianetnews.com/

I, hereby, solemnly declare that all the information made is true and correct to the

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

WORK EXPERIENCE

睛 May 2021 - Present -

Vmware

Remote

I'm a Full Stack developer, responsible for working on multiple VMware

internal products.

FrontEnd - React, Angular 14+

Technology used:

Backend - Java Spring Boot, Nodejs API - APIGETWAY, LAMBDA Vmware Cloud, Dockerized container, Sonar Cube.

Server - AWS S3 Bucket, AWS SES, Lambda Repository - Gitlab

Others - IBM WATSON, XRAY, CloudFront, AWS Cloudwatch, AWS Cognito, IdentityPool, AWS SNS, AWS SES, Microservices, Docker,

MySQL. Feb **2019** - May **2021** LEAD MEAN STACK DEVELOPER Asianetnews Media and Entertainment Pvt Ltd

Bangalore, India I'm a Lead Meanstack developer here. also working as an individual

Jan **2016** - Apr **2017**

Jan **2015** - May **2015**

Aug **2011** - Mar **2012**

CMS. It is a complete Serverless build on Angular8+. Parallelly also build 1 project without taking anyone's help. Which is based on Angular8+ and NGX-Admin **Technology used:**

Database - AWS Dynamodb, AWS Elasticsearch, AWS Kibana Server - AWS S3 Bucket, AWS SES

Backend - NodeJS

Cloudwatch, AWS Incognito, AWS SNS, Microservices, Docker. Jun 2017 - Feb 2019 LEAD DEVELOPER

Datanow Solutions LLP Bangalore, India

contributor. I am handling a team of 25+ developers, QA engineers, and Product Manager Handling more than 8+ projects. It is having only 1

backend. Follow the agile methodology and the scrum meeting daily basis **Technology used:** FrontEnd - Angular6+

Database - Mongodb, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash, Filebeat

Backend - NodeJS

GIS - MapboxGL Latest version for Clustering data

Repository - Bitbucket

Others - Microservices, Docker.

Let me find E-Services Pvt Ltd Bangalore, India

MEANSTACK DEVELOPER

I'm a mean stack developer. I spend my whole day, practically every day, experimenting with writing API and database; The project was an E-

Commerce portal **Technology used:**

Database - Mongodb, Elasticsearch, Kibana Server - AWS EC2, AWS S3 Bucket, AWS SES

Backend - NodeJS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

TANGENT PRO

Work closely with the team in early product phases to facilitate agile development methodology. Participate in software development using Agile/Scrum development process **Technology used:**

FrontEnd - Angular

Backend - NodeJS

Pathbrekerz Technology **9** Kolkata, India

in Kolkata. Backend we are using PHP and database Mysql. **Technology used:**

FrontEnd - HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Ajax

Server - AWS EC2 RECENT COMPLETE PROJECT

Roles and Responsibly: I have worked as Lead Mean Stack Developer.

Front-End & Backend part. In Front-End I have done design and

Feb 2019

implementation of backend API with node js.

Gateway, AWS

AsianetNews - Headless CMS

Architecture - Complete Serverless

Language used: - Angular 8, Node JS 8.9.4, ElasticSearch 6.0.0, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS

Database used:- AWS Dynamodb, AWS Elasticsearch, Kibana, AWS API

API Gateway e.t.c Nov **2022**

failing at what stage. I will be responsible to build a few modules like -Create order, and Move order, in Astro platform.

Database used: - AWS Dynamodb, AWS Elasticsearch

Technology used: - Serverles,, AWS Lambda, AWS EC2, AWS SNS, AWS

PERSONAL PROJECT

SES, AWS API Gateway e.t.c

Sep 2019 **Customer Complaint Forum Public**

Forum. Any Customer can come do register with us. Put some review

This Customer Complaint Forum or We can say Customer Review

May **2020**

Technology used - Angular 12+, NodeJS, MongoDB Hosting - AWS Lambda, AWS API Gateway, AWS S3 (Serverless) Website - https://rb.gy/jw0bcu

user registered with us, We are simply showing the userdata and location into the world map and datatable. Technology used - Angular 6+, NodeJS, MongoDB, MapboxGL

Codeztech Social Networking Site

Public

This is a social network commenting platform like facebook or linkedIn. I

Technology used - Angular 12+, NodeJS, MongoDB Hosting - AWS Lambda, AWS API Getway, AWS S3 (Serverless) Website - https://rb.gy/wperzp

Database - MongoDB, Postgres, Elasticsearch

contributor. Only 1 project I am handling alone. The project is headless

FrontEnd - Angular8+

API - AWS APIGETWAY, AWS LAMBDA

Pipeline - AWS CodePipeline **Repository - AWS CodeCommit** Others - AWS XRAY, AWS CloudFormation, AWS CloudFront, AWS

I work as a Lead Mean Stack Developer also worked as an individual

Server - AWS EC2, AWS S3 Bucket, AWS SES, AWS SNS, AWS Terraform Pipeline - Jenkins

FrontEnd - Angular2+

Others - Microservices, Docker

Bangalore, India I worked in a team-oriented environment for all aspects of product development (design, implementation, test, and maintenance support).

Server - AWS EC2, AWS S3 Bucket, AWS SES SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Database - Mongodb, Elasticsearch

I'm a web developer. I spend my whole day, practically every day, experimenting with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Ajax, initial my careers,

Backend - PHP Database - Mysql

Perform project design and development activities according to customer specifications. Worked on the

Technology used:- AWS Lambda, AWS EC2, AWS SNS, AWS SES, AWS Walmart Astro Project

Lambda, AWS X Ray, AWS Cloudfront, AWS Route 53, AWS

HTML5, CSS

Language used: Angular 8, Node JS 12, ElasticSearch 7.0.0, JavaScript,

Astro is the heart of Walmart, In order to check what customer order

about the about the product. Product guy can come do register as an agent, make login and they can resolved the customer problem by click on details page. Once done they can change the status active to inactive

Meanstack Crud

Public This is Simple MeanStack Crud Application with MapboxGL. Once the

Hosting - AWS Lambda, AWS API Getway, AWS S3 (Serverless) Website - https://rb.gy/gqa6h4 Dec **2020**

build this in 3 days using Mean Stack.